https://www.iftf.org/onlineprivacypolicy/

Institute For The Future
What We DoWho We AreIFTF Vantage PartnershipIFTF Foresight EssentialsForecastsWorkshopsMapsArtifacts from the FutureEventsIn the NewsMedia CenterGalleryHistory of the FutureOur WorkFeatured ProjectsGlobal LandscapePeople + TechnologyHealth + SelfPartner with IFTFIFTF VantageIFTF Foresight EssentialsResearch LabsPartnersJobsDonateContact UsPrivacy PolicyFuture NowDonate
Global LandscapePeople + TechnologyHealth + Self
Privacy Policy
IFTF Vantage2020 ResearchTen-Year ForecastAsk a FuturistLearning from LeadersIFTF Foresight EssentialsFor IndividualsFor TeamsFor CommunityResearch LabsDigital Intelligence LabEmerging Media LabEquitable Futures LabEquitable Futures: Community SpeaksWorkable HealthFuture of ImmigrationFuture of Work CommissionFood Futures LabGovernance Futures LabHealth Futures LabTech Futures LabWork + Learn Futures LabWorkable FuturesMoving Upstream 2030PartnersJobsDonateContact UsVisit UsPrivacy Policy
INTERESTED IN LEARNING MORE ABOUT IFTF?Contact us today » Who We AreWe are a network of people who work at the edges of their disciplines, with a mind toward global future implications.
Meet our network »
In the News
AI And The Death Of Exploration
Are ‘bots’ manipulating the 2020 conversation? Here’s what’s changed since 2016.
Artificial Intelligence Is Too Important to Leave to Google and Facebook Alone
See All »
Future NOW Blog
News from the Future #50
Dec 08, 2020
Searching for Signals: Tips & Tricks from IFTF Staff
Nov 24, 2020
One thing I wish I had known when I was just beginning my futures practice….
Nov 24, 2020
News from the Future #49
Nov 13, 2020
See All »
Privacy PolicyUpdated May 29, 2018
IFTF is grateful to be able to communicate with you through http://www.iftf.org/ (our “Website”). This Privacy Policy describes how IFTF (Institute for the Future) collects, uses, protects and discloses information collected when you engage with us through this platform.
IFTF believes in transparent, respectful, lawful use of personal information. By visiting the Website and/or providing the information described below, you are accepting the terms of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Website.The Types of Information IFTF CollectsPersonal Data
As a general matter, IFTF collects personally identifiable information – name, title, email address, mailing address, telephone number, social media information, demographic data – only when you voluntarily choose to provide it to us.
This happens when you:sign up to receive our newsletter or other communications;complete one of our online forms;request information or assistance;send an email or call us (including one of our employees) through the contact information provided on the Website;provide user-generated content on any part of the Website that permits it;respond to, inquire about, or apply for an employment opportunity on the Website; orinteract with IFTF’s pages or accounts on social media platforms – e.g., click on our social media links and/or provide information to us on those accounts.In addition to the above, IFTF may collect certain information that about you whenever you visit our Website. We also collect other information that relates to you whenever you visit the Website. Such information may include the Internet Protocol (IP) address of the computer, mobile device or other device you used to access the Website, the type of browser and operating system you used, the date and time you visited the Website, the Internet address of the site from which you linked to the Website, the links you follow from the Website, including to the third party processor of donations to IFTF, and the reading history and other analytics related to how visitors to the Website use and view the content we’ve provided.
Web browser cookies
IFTF may use “cookies” to enhance your experience while visiting the Website. IFTF may also use cookies to measure aggregate web statistics, such as collecting the number of visitors to the Website, the number of repeat visitors, and the most popular webpages. IFTF does not use cookies to track the activity of visitors to the Website on an individual basis.
Please note that you may choose to set your web browser to refuse cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If you choose to turn off cookies, however, some parts of the Website may not function properly.
How IFTF Uses the Information that It Collects
IFTF uses the information described in this Privacy Policy primarily to communicate with you where requested, and to enhance your experience on the Website. More specifically, we may use the information to: respond to specific inquiries and requests; add you to our mailing lists; manage, supervise or send our outreach, newsletter and other communications; contact you regarding an employment opportunity or application; process any registration or similar information you provide; improve our services, sites, facilities, events and other programmatic operations; communicate with you about a donation or processing a transaction; better understand how visitors use the Website so that we can improve the Website or its offerings; or comply with applicable law, court order, subpoena, or legal process.
If you sign up to receive the IFTF newsletter or any of our other mailings, we may contact you with information that we think will be of interest to you. IFTF will always provide an unsubscribe option with any official e-mails from our organization. If at any time you wish to stop receiving these communications, please follow the unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of the email, or send IFTF an email at ­­­­­­­­­­­­­­­­­­info@iftf.org
and ask to be removed from IFTF’s email list.
How IFTF Protects User Information
IFTF maintains data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures to help protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of your personal information. IFTF is committed to keeping your personal information safe and secure. IFTF mandates login security controls on equipment and systems, multi-factor user authentication, mandatory password expiry, digital storage encryption, routine scheduled patching and updates, and ongoing cybersecurity user training and awareness for IFTF staff.
If you provide credit card information to make a donation, your credit card information is not held by IFTF. It is collected by our third party payment processors specializing in the secure processing of credit or debit card transactions. Your credit card information is not stored by IFTF.
We review our retention periods for personal information on a regular basis. The periods of retention depend on the type of data collected, the purpose for which the data is given, and requirements of applicable law.
Sharing Personal Information
Third Party Providers
IFTF uses third party service providers to help us operate the Website and administer activities on IFTF’s behalf, such as collecting donations online, processing applications for employment, or providing analytics, maintenance or site improvement, and operational support. These third party vendors may have access to Website visitor information, but are required to protect the confidentiality of the information and to use it only for the limited purpose for which it was provided.
If you believe personal data you provided to us is being misused by a third party, please contact us at info@iftf.org.
Compliance with Law
IFTF will share personally identifiable information about those who use our Website or communicate with us when required to do so by law, or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with state and federal laws or to respond to a court order, subpoena, or search warrant. IFTF may also share personally identifiable information if we believe it is necessary to protect the rights, property, and safety of us or others.
User Consent / Other Services
From time to time, we may explicitly request consent to use your information in a manner not covered by this Policy. In such a circumstance, we would ask you to voluntarily “opt in” to agree to such use. In addition, communications through our Website often lead to additional partnership opportunities and engagements, including in relation to grantmaking, programmatic or other collaborative partnerships. IFTF may collect and use additional information in relation to those interactions, in each case as appropriate to the relationship between the parties.
Aggregated Data
IFTF may share generic aggregated demographic information not linked to any personally identifiable information regarding visitors to our Website with third parties, including in connection with maintaining, improving, and fixing any operational errors on the Website.
Third Party Websites
IFTF may provide links from the Website to other websites. IFTF does not control the content or links that appear on these third party websites and is not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from the Website. These websites and services have their own privacy policies. Browsing and interaction on any other website, including websites that have a link to or from IFTF’s Website, is subject to that website’s own terms and policies. This Privacy Policy only covers information collected through the use of the Website. In addition, IFTF does not currently respond to web browser “do not track” signals.
Compliance with Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act
Protecting the privacy of minors is especially important. For that reason, IFTF never collects information at the Website from those IFTF knows are under 16, and no part of the Website is structured specifically to attract anyone under 16. If IFTF becomes aware of having information about anyone under 16, IFTF will promptly delete the information.
California Privacy Rights
If you reside in California and have provided your personally identifiable information to IFTF, you may request information once per calendar year about IFTF’s disclosures of certain categories of your personally identifiable information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. Such requests must be submitted to IFTF at info@iftf.org.
GDPR
The Website is published in the United States and subject to laws of the United States. If you are an EU resident or citizen, you have additional rights in connection with your personal information pursuant to the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”), including the right to request a copy of your personal information that IFTF may have, and the right to request that we update, delete or anonymize that information. If you have any GDPR-specific questions or requests, please contact IFTF at info@iftf.org.
Changes to this Privacy Policy
IFTF may update this Privacy Policy at any time. When it does, IFTF will revise the updated date at the top of this page. We encourage you to frequently check this page for any changes to stay informed about what information IFTF collects and how it uses that information. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this Privacy Policy periodically and become aware of any modifications since your last visit.
Your Acceptance of These Terms
By using the Website, you signify your acceptance of this Privacy Policy, including as it is amended from time to time. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use the Website. Your continued use of the Website following the posting of changes to this Privacy Policy will be deemed your acceptance of those changes.
Contacting IFTF
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or anything relating to the Website, please contact IFTF at info@iftf.org.
The Institute for the Future is a 501(c)3 nonprofit corporation; our Tax ID number is 95-2540449. All donations are tax deductible. Additionally, your organization may offer matching grants for donations you make. Please email info@iftf.org for details.
Institute for the Future
201 Hamilton Avenue
Palo Alto, CA 94301
650.854.6322
info@iftf.org
© 2020 Institute for the Future
What We DoWho We AreIFTF Vantage PartnershipIFTF Foresight EssentialsForecastsWorkshopsMapsArtifacts from the FutureEventsIn the NewsMedia CenterGalleryHistory of the FutureOur WorkFeatured ProjectsGlobal LandscapePeople + TechnologyHealth + SelfPartner with IFTFIFTF VantageIFTF Foresight EssentialsResearch LabsPartnersJobsDonateContact UsPrivacy PolicyFuture NowDonate
